{"questions": [{"qid": 46, "answer": "Calendar", "question": "The Spanish word \u201ctrecena\u201d was coined for use in one of these systems, which was comprised of Xiuhpohualli and Tonalpohualli; that Aztec system is analogous to some of these systems that contain the Tzolk\u2019in and Haab\u2019 divisions. The \u201cLong Count\u201d one of these systems, which claims that we are currently in the (*) thirteenth Baktun, sparked fears because it supposedly predicted the end of the world in 2012. For ten points, name these systems that Mesoamerican civilizations used to keep track of lunar cycles.", "fold": "dev"}, {"qid": 47, "answer": "Photon", "question": "The power radiated by a point that is emitting these particles is given by the Larmor Formula. Surface plasmons are electrons that display behavior similar to these particles in a branch of computing devoted to them. These particles, which are represented as (*) wavy lines in Feynman Diagrams, are emitted in bremsstrahlung- and their interactions with charged particles are the subject of QED theory. For ten points, what massless particles are used in optical computing and are the quanta of light?", "fold": "dev"}, {"qid": 48, "answer": "Brownian_motion", "question": "A particle that is experiencing friction and this phenomenon is undergoing an Ornstein-Uhlenbeck process. The Fokker-Planck equation describes the velocity of a particle experiencing this phenomenon. This phenomenon provides the alternate name of a (*) Wiener Process. The Feynman Ratchet is a discredited perpetual motion machine that made use of this phenomenon in the form of heat fluctuations. For ten points, name this random motion of a particle suspended in a viscous fluid.", "fold": "dev"}, {"qid": 49, "answer": "Thirty-six_Views_of_Mount_Fuji", "question": "This object appears in the back right of a painting that shows five workers moving grain around a watermill. This object is rendered in bright red and beneath a light smattering of clouds in the painting South Wind, Clear Sky. This object appears between two (*) boats tossing in a furious storm in the painting The Great Wave off Kanagawa. Katsushika Hokusai created thirty six views of, For ten points, what Japanese landmark?", "fold": "dev"}, {"qid": 50, "answer": "Emile,_or_On_Education", "question": "A book on this topic advocates going to an artillery range to build tolerance to loud noises, has a fifth and final book that introduces the title character\u2019s love interest Sophie, and encourages religious skepticism in the \u201cProfession of Faith of the Savoyard Vicar.\u201d Mary Wollstonecraft penned (*) A Vindication of the Rights of Woman after reading a Charles Talleyrand report on this topic. Jean-Jacques Rousseau\u2019s book Emile is a treatise about, For ten points, what topic that might involve learning a trade?", "fold": "dev"}, {"qid": 51, "answer": "Oxford", "question": "John Deydras, an insane man who claimed to be Edward II, stirred up trouble when he seized this city\u2019s Beaumont Palace. The structure of the hippocampus was a central issue to a debate between Thomas Huxley and Samuel Wilberforce that was held in this city. The elimination of a set of measures proclaimed in this city touched off the (*) Second Barons\u2019 War; Henry III and his barons signed those \u201cprovisions\u201d of this city. For ten points, name this British city home to a rival college of Cambridge.", "fold": "dev"}, {"qid": 52, "answer": "House_of_Medici", "question": "A member of this family ransomed Antipope John XXIII when he was captured by Sigismund, the future Holy Roman Emperor. A ruler of this family who maintained the power of the Italic League was targeted by the Pazzi Conspiracy. Pope (*) Leo X was born into this family. A \u201cmagnificent\u201d ruler from this family patronized Sandro Botticelli as he painted the Madonna of the Magnificat. Lorenzo and Cosimo were two leaders of, For ten points, what family that held power in medieval Florence?", "fold": "dev"}, {"qid": 53, "answer": "ETA_(separatist_group)", "question": "Eva Forest wrote an account of a bombing carried out by this group under the pseudonym Julen Aguirre. Three members of this group disguised as electricians used explosives hidden under a street to blow up a Dodge Dart as it carried its passengers to morning mass in (*) Operation Ogre. This group behind the assassination of Luis Carrero Blanco officially disbanded its military wing in 2011 and its political structure in 2018. For ten points, name this terrorist group that advocated for Basque independence.", "fold": "dev"}, {"qid": 54, "answer": "The_House_on_Mango_Street", "question": "A character in this novel eats \u201cham and eggs\u201d three times a day because it is the only food whose name he knows. The main character of this novel gives names to clouds in a game played with her sister Nenny. This novel\u2019s narrator plans to leave her childhood home after she is abandoned by her friend (*) Sally at a carnival, where she is assaulted by an older man. For ten points, name this novel about the upbringing of the Latina girl Esperanza Cordero in the title abode, which was written by Sandra Cisneros.", "fold": "dev"}, {"qid": 55, "answer": "Miranda_v._Arizona", "question": "A \u201cpublic safety\u201d exclusion was added to the ruling in this Supreme Court case in New York v. Quarles, which concerned a man who discarded a firearm in a crowded grocery store. This case, which elucidated a right established two years prior in (*) Escobedo v. Illinois, concerned a man who was convicted of rape in Phoenix, but was not advised that he could speak with an attorney during his interrogation. For ten points, give this case that established namesake \u201crights,\u201d including the right to remain silent.", "fold": "dev"}, {"qid": 1, "answer": "Pascal's_triangle", "question": "This mathematical concept is demonstrated on the Galton board, on which it determines the number of paths a ball can take to reach a peg. A fractal developed by Sierpinski can be created from this construct by only displaying it's odd numbers. It's first diagonal is useless, but it's other right-to-left diagonals display well known mathematical series. One such series is composed of the triangular numbers. This concept is useful for displaying the coefficients of a binomial expansion, in which the row number displays the coefficients of binomial x+y raised to that row's number. For ten points, name this geometric construct whose namesake is that of a French Mathematician.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 2, "answer": "Bob Ross", "question": "This artist's only landscape to depict a human is simply titled \"Campfire\". Bill Alexander accused this artist of stealing his technique. In a hip-hop track, this artist tells Picasso to \"call me Jackson Pollock, because I splatter MCs\". In a cartoon portrayal, this artist threatens to \"cut you\" if you \"tell anyone that that bush is there\". Statistical analysis of this artist's body of work shows that over 90% of their paintings contain at least one tree. According to this artist, he was \"the guy who makes you scrub the latrine,\" which led to him resolving to never yell or raise his voice again after leaving the Air Force. A wet-on-wet technique, soft voice, and \"happy little trees\" characterized, for ten points, what host of The Joy of Painting who had an afro?", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 3, "answer": "Never Gonna Give You Up", "question": "In 1988, this song reached number one on American Billboards, as well as topping more than 25 charts worldwide. The London-based music video directed by Simon West begins with the red headed singer tapping his feet, which is then followed by him dancing in front of the mic. This song's lyrics attempts to tell his lover that he is thinking of \"a full commitment\", saying that she \"wouldn't get this from any other guys.\" For ten points, name this song that is the subject of a famous internet prank called \"rickrolling\".", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 4, "answer": "Array_data_structure", "question": "In earlier versions of FORTRAN this data structure could only be allocated statically so the largest possible size had to be used. It's not a hash table, but Bloom filters use this as their underlying data structure, as do heaps. Randomly accessing an element takes only constant time, and these data structures are cache friendly, unlike linked lists. For ten points, name this data structure which is a collection of elements stored in a block of contiguous memory.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 5, "answer": "United Kingdom", "question": "Though this modern-day nation does not have a formal constitution, one main instrument in its formation was signed in 1603 following the death of a monarch who was sometimes called \u201cGloriana.\u201d Its purpose was to unify three kingdoms under a monarch who is known as both \u201cthe Fourth\u201d and \u201cthe First.\" That leader survived the Gunpowder Plot and authorized a namesake translation of the Bible. For ten points, James, King of Scots, and Elizabeth I were historical rulers of what modern day country?", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 6, "answer": "Square number", "question": "The Landau-Ramanujan constant is related to the number of integers which can be expressed as the sum of two of these numbers. A generalization of a problem involving sums of these numbers is known as Waring's problem, and the Trivial Inequality implies that all of these numbers are nonnegative. Lagrange proved that any positive integer can be written as the sum of four of these numbers. These numbers are the only ones to have an odd number of factors. One of these modulo a number is known as a quadratic residue, and consecutive triangular numbers sum up to one of these numbers. The sum of the first n odd numbers is the nth one of these numbers. For ten points, name these numbers, which equal an integer times itself.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 7, "answer": "Rum Rebellion", "question": "A political cartoon by an unknown artist from this event depicts two men men in a red coats dragging out its target from underneath a bed. That target of this event had previously ordered the boarding of the HMS Porpoise before he arrived at the colony at which it took place. This event was triggered by a failed attempt to arrest John Macarthur. For ten points, name this alliterative rebellion that deposed William Bligh as governor of New South Wales, named after a type of alcohol typically made from sugarcane.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 8, "answer": "University of Chicago", "question": "This university's origins can be traced back to 1856, when Senator Stephen A. Douglas offered a plot of land for the university to be established. In 1939, this university disbanded its football team after the president sought to de-emphasize varsity athletics, and would withdraw from a Division I conference seven years later. This university is famous for associations with renowned scientists such as Robert Millikan and Enrico Fermi, with the latter assembling a nuclear reactor under the university's football field. Outside of its science program, the university has been known for its exceptional school of economics, which produced the famous Milton Friedman. For ten points, name this Midwestern university, whose athletic teams are called the Maroons.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 9, "answer": "Speed of sound", "question": "The \u201ccritical\u201d properties found at this point are notated with asterisks, and their ratios with their corresponding stagnation values equal the quantity 2 over quantity 1 plus the heat capacity ratio all raised to some power. At an aperture near this point, when downstream pressure drops below a critical value, the flow rate becomes independent of downstream pressure, or \u201cchoked\u201d, as can be seen in the convergent-divergent nozzle designed by Gustaf de Laval. Flows near this point are typically simplified by being treated as isentropic. The Rankine-Hugoniot conditions model a phenomenon that occurs above this point. Density fluctuations begin to be considered significant at around 30% this value, above which flows are considered  compressible. Above this point, shockwaves begin to form. This phenomenon can be defined as the square root of bulk modulus over density. For ten points, name this value found in the denominator of the Mach number, equal to about 340 meters per second for air.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 10, "answer": "United States", "question": "A religious leader based in this country created the Final Testament, a translation of the Qur\u2019an, and claimed to have found a code in the Qur\u2019an based on the number 19. That religious leader was Rashad Khalifa, the founder of United Submitters International, a Qur\u2019anist movement. During a pilgrimage to Mecca, a leader from this country took the name el-Hajj Malik el-Shabazz, and wrote a letter describing pilgrims \u201cof all colors, from blue-eyed blondes to black-skinned Africans,\u201d which state that  \u201c[This country] needs to understand Islam, because this is the one religion that erases from its society the race problem.\u201d For ten points, name this country where Noble Drew Ali founded the Moorish Science Temple and Wallace Fard Muhammad founded the Nation of Islam.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 11, "answer": "Philadelphia", "question": "In this city, Alexander Calder's father sculpted the Swann memorial fountain. A memorial in this city honors the victims of a 2013 building collapse that killed 6 people at a Salvation Army location. In 2006, this city raised 68 million dollars to keep Thomas Eakins's the Gross Clinic in the city. Eakins also painted his friend Max Schmitt rowing on the Schuylkill river in this city. For ten points, name this location of Independence Hall, the largest city in Pennsylvania.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 12, "answer": "Cannibalism", "question": "James V. McConnell encouraged flatworms to engage in this behavior in order to test whether doing this affected memory. An atypical morph of the tiger salamander is distinguished at the age of four weeks by physical changes to their jaws which increase their efficiency in this activity. The common name of the Latrodectus genus is a reference to their participation in this behavior as a mating practice, which is speculated as a way for female specimens to acquire additional nutrition. If you do this in Papua New Guinea, you acquire an elevated risk of contracting the prion disease kuru, which is spread through infected brain tissue. For ten points, name this practice which is taboo in humans, the consumption of the flesh of one's own species.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 13, "answer": "Tuberculosis", "question": "Depending on where they occur, lesions caused by this disease can be given a \"focus\" named after Simon, Ghon, or Ranke. The only vaccine currently available for this disease is the attenuated BCG strain. Because the causative agent of this disease has a particularly waxy capsule, an acid-fast stain must be used to identify it. About a third of all people are infected with the causative agent of this disease, which causes more deaths annually than any other infectious disease. For ten points, name this disease caused by bacteria of the genus Mycobacterium.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 14, "answer": "450", "question": "This number is one hundred and fifty less than the number of horses that rode into the Valley of Death. This number is one hundred and fifty more than the number of Spartans at Thermopylae. This number is thirty more than a number often associated with cannabis. For ten points, what number is equivalent to nine times fifty?", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 15, "answer": "Skeleton", "question": "In 2011, David Romo, the founder of a church dedicated to a deity depicted in this physical form, was arrested for involvement in a kidnapping ring. On the first day of every month, a rosary ceremony dedicated to that deity depicted in this physical form is held by Enriqueta Romero at a shrine in Tepito. Jos\u00e9 Guadalupe Posada depicted one of these things wearing a feathered hat, known as the Catrina, which is a prominent symbol in a holiday that coincides with All Saints\u2019 Day. A female deity depicted in this physical form is often associated with criminality due to her worship by members of drug cartels; that Mexican folk deity is known as Santa Muerte. For ten points, name these things, which feature prominently as symbols during Day of the Dead.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 16, "answer": "Bill Clinton", "question": "On \"The Critic\", this man was replaced by a drunken animatronic bear from the Country Bear Jamboree but nobody seemed to notice. This man was edited to appear in the film \"Contact\", which prompted an angry statement from Mike McCurry. He was portrayed by Dennis Quaid in \"The Special Relationship\", who ate McDonald's every day to prepare for the role. A fictionalized version of this man named Henry Burton, a charismatic Southern governor running for the Democratic nomination, is portrayed by John Travolta in \"Primary Colors\". For ten points, name this American president who played the saxophone on an appearance on the Arsenio Hall Show.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 17, "answer": "San Francisco", "question": "The first plague epidemic in the continental U.S. was located in this city. In 1851, the Committee of Vigilance was formed in this city in response to rapid population growth. It was the location of the Six Gallery reading, and the United Nations charter was also signed in this city. The White Night Riots began after George Moscone and Harvey Milk were assassinated in this city in 1978. For ten points, name this Northern California city that was the site of a 1906 earthquake.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 18, "answer": "Ulysses S. Grant", "question": "Ninety years before the bay of pigs invasion, this man faced political pressure to intervene militarily in Cuba but did not do so. This man and Harry Truman share a middle initial that doesn't stand for anything. This man believed that he may have been an intended secondary target of a famous assassination and might have been killed were it not for his wife turning down the invitation from his commander in chief to go to the theater that night.  During his retirement he visited Germany and met a famous Berliner. His memorial was turned over to the National Park Service in 1958. After his death, the sales of his biography supported his wife. For ten points, who is this national hero?", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 19, "answer": "Bread", "question": "There is a special term to describe someone who earns enough money to obtain this for himself and his family. The Bible says that man cannot live by this alone and the Lord's Prayer pleads for a daily dose of this. A popular idiom implies that the idea to sell this item pre-sliced was an incredible invention. Another idiom predicts what will happen if you drop a slice of this that has been buttered on only one side. For ten points, what is this food?", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 20, "answer": "Horse", "question": "In Hindu myth, Tumburu gave Yudhishthira a hundred of these. Hernan Cortes used fifteen to help defeat the Aztecs. Shakespeare has a desperate Richard III offer to trade his kingdom for one of these. A 1960s TV show had one that could talk named Mister Ed. Traditionally, American cowboys do much of their work on the back of one of these. Metal shoes are often used to protect their feet. For ten points, what is this thing that you are more likely to see at a farm than a zoo?", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 21, "answer": "The Scarlet Letter", "question": "Although Edwin Percy Whipple criticized the \"morbid intensity\" of this novel, George Eliot applauded it as one of the most \"indigenous and masterly productions in American literature.\" The narrator frequently mentions Anne Hutchinson, speculating that the rosebush outside the prison door exists where Hutchinson once stood. This novel deals with sin and guilt, as Arthur Dimmesdale carves an \"A\" into his chest to match the one that Hester Prynne must wear on her chest. For ten points, name this Hawthorne novel that takes place in Puritan Massachusetts.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 22, "answer": "Republican National Convention", "question": "In 2016, Kerry Woolard and Joni Ernst were among the people who spoke at this event, which happens every four years. The first of this event took place in Pittsburgh in 1856, but the first one to nominate a successful president was in 1860. When this event occurred in 1924, it was the first to ever be broadcasted over radio. When it occurred in 1940, it was the first time any of this type of event was broadcast on live television for any party. For ten points, what event occurred in Cleveland, Ohio in 2016 and chooses the presidential nominee for the Republican Party?", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 23, "answer": "Turkey", "question": "A journalist in this country, Rifat \u00c7etin, was given a suspended prison sentence for comparing this country\u2019s president to Gollum from Lord of the Rings, and in 2013 a group called \u201cErgenekon\u201d was alleged to be plotting against this country\u2019s government. In July 2016, the actions of a group called the \u201cPeace at Home Council\u201d resulted in the occupation of Taksim Square and the closure of the Bosphorus Bridge in this country. For ten points, name this country where Recep Tayyip Erdogan governs from Ankara, the site of an alleged coup.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 24, "answer": "Heart", "question": "An e. e. cummings poem about carrying one of these objects includes the lines \u201chere is the deepest secret nobody knows,\u201d and the speaker of a Byron poem asks a \u201cMaid of Athens\u201d to give back one of these objects before they part ways. These body parts are \u201ctorn and bleeding\u201d in Paul Laurence Dunbar\u2019s \u201cWe Wear the Mask,\u201d and John Donne asked a \u201cthree-personed God\u201d to batter this organ. This internal organ is a \u201cLonely Hunter\u201d in the title of a Carson McCullers novel. For ten points, name this internal organ which is \u201cTell-Tale\u201d in an Edgar Allan Poe story.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 25, "answer": "If—", "question": "This is the first word in the title of a Faulkner novel containing the stories \"Wild Palms\" and \"Old Man.\" That title quotes Psalm 137, which is about the destruction of Jerusalem. According to Plutarch, this word was given as a laconic reply to Philip of Macedon by the Spartan ephors when he warned what he would do to the city should he invade. This word also titles a poem that references a game of \"pitch-and-toss\" and \"sixty seconds of distance run.\" That poem concludes with the line \"You'll be a Man, my son!\" and is written by Rudyard Kipling. For ten points, name this two-letter word often paired with \"Then\" in conditional statements.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 26, "answer": "China", "question": "An opera by a composer born in this country uses the mistreatment of two fallen angels as an allegory for human trafficking. In one opera set in this country, slave girls dance to a fantasia on \u201cGreensleeves\u201d, reused from the \u201cDas Frauengemach\u201d movement of an earlier suite. That Busoni opera premiered on a double bill with his Arlecchino. The \u201cRussian Sailors\u2019 Dance\u201d appears in a ballet that takes place in this country, Gliere\u2019s The Red Poppy. The most famous aria from an opera set in this country begins with the protagonist singing the title phrase on a high D, then repeating it an octave lower. In that opera set in this country, a prince commands the stars to fade before declaring \u201cvincero\u201d [VIN-cheh-rho] in the aria \u201cNessun dorma\u201d. For ten points, give this setting of Puccini\u2019s Turandot.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 27, "answer": "The Catcher in the Rye", "question": "The narrator of this novel claims that he \"likes it when somebody gets excited about something. It's nice\". At another point in this novel, the same narrator states that \"When you're dead, they really fix you up\". Despite that somewhat positive quip on death, the narrator of this novel expresses that he wishes time would stand still, much like the exhibits in a certain museum. That museum is New York City's Museum of Natural History. The narrator of this novel stares at ducks on a frozen pond in Central Park, and is a \"terrific liar\". That narrator is Holden Caulfield. For ten points, name this novel by J.D. Salinger in which Holden Caulfield leaves Pencey Prep and roams New York City.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 28, "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "question": "According to his advisers, this man had multiple pillow fights with Leonard Wood while holding his highest office. During this man's tenure, he forced Binger Hermann to resign following the discovery of corruption between that man and the commissioner of the Indian Service. This president passed the Hepburn Act, establishing federal control of railroad states, as well as the Pure Food and Drug Act. This president mediated a meeting between two feuding nations over the division of the Sakhalin Island. That meeting took place in Portsmouth, New Hampshire and effectively ended the Russo-Japanese War. For ten points, identify this man who became president after the assassination of William McKinley.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 29, "answer": "Resonance (chemistry)", "question": "An effect of this name named for Fermi occurs due to mixing between vibrational modes with identical symmetries in vibrational spectroscopy. This phenomenon is the principle behind a form of Raman spectroscopy which enhances signal by tuning the lasers frequency near that of an electronic transition. This phenomenon can enhance Raman signal by up to an E4 enhancement for molecules adsorbed onto rough metal surfaces or nanoparticles. This phenomenon can be used to analyze the binding of molecules to functionalized gold or silver surfaces, and is responsible for the effectiveness of SERS. When a microwave matches the energy of a transition created due to Zeeman splitting, this phenomenon occurs, resulting in a peak in ESR. For ten points, name this phenomenon in which an oscillating system increases its amplitude when driven at a certain frequency.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 30, "answer": "Kidney", "question": "When skeletal muscle is damaged due to crush injury, this organ is often damaged as a result of the rhabdomyolysis. A low purine diet is recommended for people with xanthine oxidase deficiency, which can cause damage to this organ, which can also suffer from buildup of IgA. Testing the function of this organ is commonly done before use of gadolinium contrast agents to reduce the risk of NSF. Those tests of this organ\u2019s help typically include the BUN and serum creatinine levels. Disease of this organ can lead to formation of crystals of \u201curemic frost\u201d on the skin, and may result in proteinuria or hematuria. The function of this organ can be calculated through the GFR, or the glomerular filtration rate. Failure of this organ results in the need for dialysis. For ten points, name this organ responsible for filtering the blood.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 31, "answer": "Oklahoma", "question": "This state is the birthplace of businessman T. Boone Pickens and former U.N. Ambassador Jeane Kirkpatrick, and this modern-day state was the site of the Sequoyah Constitutional Convention in 1905. Race riots in this state resulted in the destruction of \u201cBlack Wall Street\u201d in 1921, and the Alfred P. Murrah Federal Building in this state\u2019s capital was the site of a 1995 terrorist attack. Thousands of Native Americans were forcibly relocated to this modern-day state on the Trail of Tears. For ten points, name this \u201cSooner State\u201d whose major cities include Muskogee and Tulsa.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 32, "answer": "Alcohol", "question": "These functional groups are produced by ring opening of epoxides. Lithium aluminum hydride can completely reduce a carbonyl group to this functional group. A mixture of one of these substances with 4% water forms a positive azeotrope. One of these substances, the most commonly used biofuel, can be produced by fermentation of corn or yeast in bread. Theisopropyl type of these substances is used in hand sanitizer. For ten points, name this functional group characterized by a hydroxyl compound, the simplest one of which is methanol.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 33, "answer": "Persian language", "question": "In the prologue of one work written in this language, the speaker describes an object that moves \u201cmen and women to tears.\u201d \u201cThe Song of the Reed-Flute\u201d was written in this language, and serves as the prologue for the poetry collection Spiritual Couplets. Another poetry collection written in this language describes how \u201cthe moving finger writes,\u201d and consists of 51 quatrains. In an Edward Fitzgerald translation of a poetry collection in this language, the speaker wishes for \u201ca jug of wine, a loaf of bread, and Thou beside [him].\u201d For ten points, name this language used by Omar Khayyam to write the Rubaiyat.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 34, "answer": "The Death of Socrates", "question": "John Boyndell wrote to Sir Joshua Reynolds that this painting was \u201cthe greatest effort of art since the Sistine Chapel and the stanze of Raphael\u201d. At the right of this painting, a man in red grasps the bridge of his nose as he holds his other arm upward, facing away from the central figure. That central figure\u2019s thigh is being grasped by a man to his right in orange, Crito. A young man in red to the left looks away as he hands the central figure a cup. For ten points, name this Jacques-Louis David painting that depicts the execution of an ancient Athenian philosopher.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 35, "answer": "The President", "question": "Two paintings by Andy Thomas show members of this group of people playing cards and playing pool, and are named Grand Ol' Gang and Calling the Blue, respectively. Another painting of one of these people shows two horses in a boat surrounded by icebergs in the right background. Another painting of a member of this group shows a slightly opened window with a red curtain in the background. The central figure in that painting holds a sword in his left hand, while extending his right hand over a table with books underneath.An unfinished portrait of one of these people shows that man's face encircled in front of a brown wall. Those two paintings were produced by Gilbert Stuart. Emanuel Leutze painted one of these people leading troops to the Battle of Trenton. For ten points, name these leaders of a North American Country.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 36, "answer": "Sailing to Byzantium", "question": "In a follow up to this poem the speaker describes a \"miracle, bird or golden handiwork\" which will show scorn to \"all complexities of mire or blood.\" That creature is a reference to an item in this poem which is \"of hammered gold and gold enamelling\" which will \"keep a drowsy Emperor awake\" or sing of \"what is past, or passing, or to come\". The speaker laments his mortality and wishes to be gathered \"into the artifice of eternity\". For ten points, name this poem about a journey to an ancient empire by W.B. Yeats.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 37, "answer": "-1", "question": "This number is related to Euler\u2019s identity, and is used as a \u201csentinel value\u201d in software development to show that a variable contains no useful information.  This number is used in programming languages to index the last or second to last item of an array, depending on whether that number was 1 or 0.  Multiplying a number by this number is equivalent to changing its sign, which is proved by using the distributive law.  For ten points, name this number, which is the additive inverse of 1.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 38, "answer": "Ohio", "question": "The National Republican Senatorial Committee claimed that a then-current Senator from this state had \u201ccommunist sympathies\u201d in 1987.  A recent gubernatorial candidate for this state notably was found not to have a driver's license, leading to him only winning 2 counties in this state\u2019s gubernatorial election, including losing his home county. This state faced a federal civil rights lawsuit for searching the government records of Joseph Wurzelbacher. A congressional district in this state has faced criticism for possibly not being contiguous, and has been deemed by activists as \u201cThe Mistake by the Lake.\u201d One of this state\u2019s current Senators defeated its treasurer, Josh Mandel, in the 2012 elections, while the other defeated former governor Ted Strickland in 2016. For ten points, name this state represented in the Senate by Sherrod Brown and Rob Portman, a notable swing state.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 39, "answer": "Lawyer", "question": "Gamblers of this profession appear in works titled The Alchemist and The Bet respectively. One member of this profession is named Metzger, and aids Oedipa Maas in Thomas Pynchon\u2019s The Crying of Lot 49. In Yukio Mishima\u2019s Sea of Fertility Tetralogy, one of these named Shigekuni Honda identifies the reincarnated Kiyoaki. Elmer Gantry joins this profession after retiring from football, and in Great Expectations one named Jaggers sends money to Pip. For ten points, name this profession, which includes Bernard from Death of a Salesman and Atticus Finch.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 40, "answer": "The_Stranger_(novel)", "question": "In this novel, a character is bothered by the \"big flies that keep landing on his face\" while speaking with a civil officer. At the end of this novel, the protagonist is cooled by the \"smells of night, earth, and salt air\", contrasting with the beginning of the novel, where he is continually plagued by the heat. That scene occurs after a character, enraged, states that \"There were only privileged people.\" At the turning point in this novel, a man discharges his gun four times, which was like \"knocking four quick times on the door of unhappiness.\" For ten points, name this novel with an absurdist hero, written by Albert Camus.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 41, "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "question": "An aircraft carrier bearing this man's name hosted the \"Mission Accomplished\" speech. A city named after this man is the site of the only unicameral state legislature. A tunnel named after this man was the second tunnel built to cross the Hudson River. An organization named for this man fought against Francisco Franco's forces. A building dedicated to him was the site of the \"I have a dream\" speech. For ten points, name this subject of the portrait on the penny.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 42, "answer": "Ghosts_(play)", "question": "A play titled for these entities features a man who is \"often very careless with matches,\" as well as a character who suffers from the \"softening of the brain.\" Another of these entities is followed by a character who \"waxes desperate with imagination\"; that entity repeatedly calls upon Horatio and Marcellus to \"swear\" on a sword. In another play, Pastor Manders is told \"we are all\" these entities by Mrs. Alving. For ten points, name these supernatural entities that title a Henrik Ibsen play.", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 43, "answer": "Brigham Young", "question": "Before becoming territorial governor his only political experience was as a city council member in Nauvoo, Illinois. As territorial governor, he gave women the right to vote before all but one state had done so. The largest university in Idaho is named after him. He was treated harshly by Congress partly because they did not accept his practice of having multiple wives. For ten points, who is this religious and political leader?", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 44, "answer": "Atlanta", "question": "Opponents of this city\u2019s public transit system have called it a scheme for \u201cmoving Africans rapidly through\u201d this city. Oscar winner Hattie McDaniel was unable to attend the gala for the premiere of Gone with the Wind due to racial segregation laws in this city. Booker T. Washington proposed this city\u2019s namesake compromise in a speech given at the Cotton States and International Expo in, for ten points, what home of the world\u2019s busiest airport and capital of Georgia?", "fold": "test"}, {"qid": 45, "answer": "United_States_presidential_election,_1968", "question": "In this election year, George Romney withdrew from Republican primaries following comments that he was \u201cbrainwashed,\u201d and supporters of Eugene McCarthy went \u201cclean for Gene\u201d during the New Hampshire primary. That year saw vice presidential nominee Curtis LeMay earn controversy for supporting the potential use of tactical nuclear weapons, and Richard Daley was criticized by Abe Richoff for the use of \u201cgestapo tactics\u201d at the Democratic National Convention. George Wallace ran on the third-party American Independent ticket in this year. For ten points, name this election year where Richard Nixon won his first term as president.", "fold": "test"}]}
